Turn up the volume on your imagination.
Piece by Piece is a animation, family, music film directed by Morgan Neville.
A unique cinematic experience that invites audiences on a vibrant
journey through the life of cultural icon Pharrell Williams.
Told through the lens of LEGO® animation, turn up the volume on your imagination
and witness the evolution of one of music's most innovative minds.
Pharrell Williams (voice), played by Pharrell Williams.
Chad Hugo (voice), played by Chad Hugo.
Gwen Stefani (voice), played by Gwen Stefani.
Kendrick Lamar (voice), played by Kendrick Lamar.
Timbaland (voice), played by Timbaland.
Justin Timberlake (voice), played by Justin Timberlake.
Piece by Piece is a 2024 American animated biographical documentary comedy
film co-produced, co-written and directed by Morgan Neville.
It follows the life and career of American musician Pharrell Williams, who stars
in the film, through the lens of Lego animation, or brickfilm.
Produced by The Lego Group, Neville's Tremolo Productions, and Williams' I Am Other, Piece by Piece marks the
sixth theatrical Lego-based film and the first under Universal Pictures' run of their film rights.
Alongside Williams and Neville, the film stars the voices of Gwen Stefani, Kendrick Lamar, Timbaland, Justin Timberlake,
Busta Rhymes, Jay-Z, Dogman, Kevin Gates, Young M.A, the Deep and Snoop Dogg as Lego versions of themselves.
Williams had considered creating a film about his life since 2013; however, serious plans for a documentary
in animated musical form started in 2019 following a discussion between Williams and Neville.
Neville interviewed with Williams' associates remotely during the COVID-19
pandemic, and later shot certain live-action scenes with him.
The Lego Group created minifigure pieces that better represent the styles of African-American culture, as
well as Williams's frequent collaborators, and designed new pieces for music equipment.
Williams, who also produces, wrote five original songs for the film.
Piece by Piece premiered at the 51st Telluride Film Festival on August 30, 2024, and was released theatrically in the United
States and Canada on October 11 through Focus Features, with Universal handling international distribution.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics, but was a box office
failure, grossing $10.7 million against a $16 million budget.
The film explores themes of musical, biography, coming
of age, live action and animation, lego.
The tone is lighthearted.